So, that's all for now.
那么以上呢
These are Wutong Glass' new products
就是我为大家介绍的
that I wanted to share with you.
梧桐玻璃的一些新品
Please stay tuned for more.
大家敬请期待
Thank you, Ms. Geng.
耿老师辛苦了
Please take a break
您可以到贵宾室
in the VIP room.
休息片刻
No, it's fine.
不用了
I need to go to the restroom to refine my make-up.
我想去洗手间补个妆
Alright, I'll go with you.
好那我陪你一起
I'm cool.
不用了
I can manage on my own.
我自己可以
Give me my purse.
把包给我
OK, got it.
好收到了
Please wrap this for her.
帮这位女士包一下
OK, thanks.
好 谢谢
Hello.
您好
How may I help you?
有什么可以帮您
What's the meaning behind this one?
这有什么寓意
[This]
这个
[is a souvenir from our press conference.]
是我们发布会的纪念品
[It features the famous zodiac signs.]
著名的十二生肖
[It's for a kid's first birthday celebrations.]
也是给孩子抓周用的
[It's made of ultra-thin glass,]
它的材质呢
[just one hundred microns thick.]
是一百微米的极薄玻璃
First birthday?
抓周
Good.
好
I'll take this one.
那我先付钱吧
OK.
好嘞
It didn't go through.
没成功
Let's try again.
那再一次
OK.
行
Maybe your credit card...
您这卡是不是
Thank you.
谢谢
Is there a problem?
有什么问题吗
It didn't get through.
没收到
How could that happen?
怎么会
Er...
这
Hello.
您好
I'm an account manager
我是代瑞银行的
from Dairui Bank.
客户经理
Let me take a look at your card.
要不我帮您看看卡
Thank you for your help.
麻烦你了
No problem at all.
不会
Your card has expired.
您的卡过期了
Typically, a credit card is valid for
一般信用卡使用期限
three to five years.
是三到五年
You should reach out to your account manager
您找客户经理
to help you apply for a new one.
帮您重新办一张
Then just activate it,
然后激活一下
and you'll be good to go.
就可以使用了
But this one won't work.
不过今天使用不了了
Thank you.
谢谢你啊
So,
那
I'm sorry,
不好意思
I can't make the purchase.
我买不了了
It's alright.
没事
How about this?
要不
Use my card.
刷我的
You can pay me back later.
回头您转给我就行
Are you sure?
可以吗
Yeah.
可以
Got it!
收到了
OK.
好
Please wrap it up for me.
那你帮我包起来吧
Can I add you on WeChat?
我可以加你个微信吗
I'll transfer the money to you later.
回头我把钱转给你
Alright.
好
Thank you so much!
谢谢你啊
You're welcome.
不客气
You look stunning.
您长得真好看
What a waste of time.
白跑一趟
We waited nearly two hours.
等了快两小时
But Mr. Xia still didn't show up.
夏总还是没来
I just found out
我刚才打听到
that Mr. Xing from section two
二部的老邢
ambushed him at the hotel.
把人堵在酒店了
Originally, Mr. Xia
本来这个夏总
wasn't planning to meet anyone.
谁也不见的
But Mr. Xing
这老邢
dressed up as a
把自己打扮成个
hotel staff member.
酒店服务员
He even made a name tag,
还弄了个工牌
looking quite convincing,
像模像样的
and ambushed Mr. Xia right
把人直接堵在了
at the door of his suite.
房间门口
[That was quite a sneaky tactic.]
这手段也是够脏的
We are sales.
做营销吗
It's all about performance.
靠的就是业绩
For a big project like
像惟纪公司
Weiji Company,
这么大的项目
it's normal for
邢总
Mr. Xing to
使点儿手段
use some tricks.
也是很正常的
But you,
倒是你啊
that's quite some inside scoop you got.
小道消息来得还挺快
Folks from section two
这二部的人口风
are pretty loose-lipped.
也挺松啊
Well, I've been working for Dairui
那我在代瑞
for so many years.
干了这么多年了
It's normal to have
有一两个交心的朋友
one or two close friends.
也很正常嘛
But don't worry,
不过你放心啊
I may brag a lot,
我这人虽然废话多
but when it comes to business,
但遇到真事
I'm very discreet.
嘴很严的
They can't pick up
我们这边的
on anything
任何动向
from
他们
our team.
摸不出来一点
What is it?
什么东西
What is
什么东西这么
on the seat?
硌我屁股
It belongs to your secret lover.
你那关系特殊的对象
What lover?
什么对象不对象的
Mind your own business.
管好你自己的事情
What business do I have?
我能有什么事啊
You have a crush on Rao Jing.
你喜欢饶静
Do you think I can't see that?
真当我看不出来啊
I have a crush on her?
我喜欢她
How could I possibly like her?
我怎么可能会喜欢她呢
I wasn't asking you.
我也没再问你啊
I was simply making a statement.
我说的是陈述句
What statement?
什么陈述句啊
She might not even be interested in me.
人家不一定瞧得上我
She looks thrilled.
这么开心
Could it be that
难道
she officially started dating the boss?
她真的被领导转正了
But,
但是
the hair tie in
领导车上那个
his car doesn't
头绳
look like something Yuhui would use.
也不像是小唐会用的呀
Whose hair tie was left in the boss' car?
谁的头绳落领导车里了
[Is it that special,]
是那个特殊的
[mysterious girl?]
神秘人物吗
[She officially started dating the boss?]
转正了
What are you guys talking about?
什么东西啊
Get back to work.
回去工作
A hair tie in the boss' car?
领导车里的头绳
You must have seen things.
你会不会是看错了呀
[How could there be a hair tie?]
怎么能有头绳呢
[Maybe it's]
说不定
[a rubber band]
橡皮筋
[or something else.]
或者绑别的东西
- It's all possible. - Am I blind to you?
都有可能 我瞎呀
There's a Shiba Inu on it.
那上面有只柴犬
[Shiba Inu?]
柴犬
I remember someone wearing it before.
我记得好像谁戴过
Xiaoning,
小涂
didn't you
你之前是不是
have one before?
也戴过一个
A Shiba Inu hair tie?
上面有柴犬的头绳来着
Maybe.
好像是吧
I can't really remember.
不太记得了
[Recently,]
最近
[that hair tie has become quite popular.]
那个头绳挺流行的
A lot of girls have it.
好多人都有
You've got one too, right?
你 你也有吧
Yeah, it's pretty trendy.
对啊是挺流行的
[Is there really something going on]
他们两个
[between them?]
不会真有什么吧
The group photo we took last time
上次咱们那个大合照
has been posted on the internal network.
发行里内网了
Check the homepage.
首页
Go take a look, guys.
都去看一眼啊
OK.
好
Zhao Fanggang, did
赵方刚
you hire that photographer?
那摄影师是不是你找的
Yeah.
是啊
No wonder
怪不得
he made your face look so small
把你脸拍得那么小
and made mine look so big,
把我脸拍得那么大
like a big pancake.
像个大饼似的
[Were you doing that on purpose?]
你是不是故意的
I think you look pretty good.
我觉得拍得挺好看的呀
Broad-minded and broad face.
心宽体胖
Get lost.
给我滚
Xiaoning,
小涂
you look pretty good in that shot.
你这个拍得挺好呀
[You standing next to the boss,]
这你跟领导站一起
[at first glance,]
这乍一看
[it looks a bit like]
有点像
[a wedding photo.]
结婚照
Nah, not even close.
这哪儿像了
It's worlds apart.
差了十万八千里呢
It's not even a luxury brand
又不是什么高奢品牌
which may cost a couple of thousands.
七八千
That hair tie of yours is everywhere.
你那头绳满大街都是
Just deny it.
到时候你咬死不承认
You'll be fine.
不就得了
I might be able to get through it.
糊弄倒是能糊弄过去
But living like this every day,
可你说这日子天天过得
always on edge...
提心吊胆地
I've been very careful already.
我已经很小心了
I have to be extra careful.
我还得小心再小心
It's exhausting!
我累不累啊
So,
所以说嘛
all your worries for now
你现在这些担心啊
are just a waste of energy.
都是白费工夫
You two just take it as it comes,
你们俩就兵来将挡
deal with whatever comes your way.
见招拆招喽
It's been so long without being discovered,
都这么久了没被发现
which shows your acting skills are solid.
说明你俩演技过硬
You'll be fine.
没问题的
I hope so.
希望吧
I'd like to check out that store.
那家店我想去看看
Hey, stop!
不许去
You've bought so much already.
多少东西了
I've only got two arms.
我一共就两只胳膊
Just one more, that's it.
最后一家店
If you keep buying,
你再买的话
my arms will break.
我胳膊要断了
Wait until Qi Yu is free.
你等齐郁有时间
You can ask him to shop with you.
让他陪你来逛
The name "Qi Yu"
齐郁这两个字
is today's taboo word.
是今天的禁忌词
Taboo?
禁忌
What's wrong?
怎么了
What did he do wrong?
他犯了什么天条啦
At least fill me in on the details
你好歹让我知道
about what was going on.
怎么回事吧
He actually returned the leather shoes
他居然把我费尽心思
that I carefully selected for him.
给他买的皮鞋给退了
Those were meant to be
那可是我给他选的
a gift for his new job.
入职礼物
And then,
然后呢
he said it was because
他说是因为
the money I used to buy the shoes
我给他买鞋的钱
came from my dad.
是我爸的
He didn't want to spend my dad's money.
他不想花我爸的钱
Everything I've had since childhood:
我从小到大
food, drinks, toys
吃的喝的玩的用的
have all been paid for
哪一样花的
with my dad's money!
不是我爸的钱
Wasn't he saying I'm living off my dad?
他这不是在说我啃老吗
He definitely didn't mean it that way.
他肯定不是那个意思
That's exactly what he meant.
他就是那个意思
Now he's become
现在我看他又
a police officer,
当上警察了
so full of righteousness,
正义感爆棚
even pointing fingers at me.
闲事管到我头上来了
That wasn't
你这么说
really fair to him.
你觉得合适吗
What's not fair about it?
怎么不合适了
You know him
他是什么样的人呢
better than anyone.
你最了解
And I know you
你是什么样的人
You're just
你现在就是在这儿
venting right now.
说气话
Anyway,
总之呢
he took it upon himself
他自作主张
to return the shoes I bought him.
把我给他买的鞋退了
That's his fault.
那就是他的不对啊
You can tell him he's wrong.
那他不对你可以说他
You could even have a fight with him.
你甚至可以跟他吵一架
Regardless,
不管怎么样
you should call him over now.
你现在打电话把他叫来
I'm not taking
我可不负责
all those
你这大包小包的
to your car.
给你拎上车啊
Fine, I'll call him.
打就打
I just need someone to carry the stuff.
不就是个提包的吗
Weiyi.
惟依
The weather is lovely.
今天天气不错
Let's go out for a walk.
我们出去走走呗
I'll see how you'll explain yourself.
我看你怎么把这事编圆
A couple of days ago,
我前两天
I was playing basketball with Yuheng.
不是跟老纪打球嘛
We brought up the mortgage issue.
提到那个买房贷款的事
Who needs a loan?
谁要贷款啊
If we're getting married in the future,
我们两个以后结婚
we need a place to live, right?
总得有一个家吧
With my current income,
以我目前的收入来说
the down payment is quite challenging.
首付确实困难
Let alone paying in full.
更别说全款了
Just take your time.
那就慢慢来呗
No one is rushing you.
又没人催你
True, no one is rushing me,
是没人催我
but since I want to be with you,
可我既然要和你在一起
I need to be able to support
总得有能力负担起
our life together.
我们两个人的生活吧
[I have to take good care of you.]
我得照顾好你
Because I know
因为我知道
Ling Weiyi has high standards,
凌惟依的标准呢
and they're right here.
在这儿
They might even be higher.
甚至可能更高
I might not be able to meet them now.
我还够不着
But I truly believe that
不过我相信
in the future, I'll definitely meet them.
以后一定可以
[I don't want you to]
我不想你因为
[lower your standards]
跟我在一起
[just because you're with me.]
就降低自己的生活标准
[I don't want you to lower your standards.]
委屈你
And about those shoes,
还有今天那双鞋
how could I
你说
not be happy
女朋友送我礼物
when my girlfriend gives me a gift?
能不开心吗
I was thrilled.
我特别开心
I was truly happy about it.
打心眼里高兴
But I don't want to
可我不希望
spend your money or your dad's money
这么理所当然
however I please.
花你和叔叔的钱
That was my gift to you,
那是我送给你的
for your new job!
入职礼物啊
It's likely that this is the only time
很有可能你这辈子
you start a job in your life.
就入这一回职
This is really meaningful,
这很有纪念意义的
alright?
好不好
Can't you just accept it this time
你就不能先把礼物收下
and save your argument for my next buy.
下回再较这个劲儿吗
Don't worry,
你放心
I've got it all figured out.
我都想好了
On top of my daily expenses,
除去日常的生活开销呢
I'll save the rest of my salary.
剩下的钱我攒一攒
I'll be able to buy those shoes back
很快就能把那双鞋
real soon.
买回来
By then,
到时候
I'll wear them with my police uniform
搭配一身警服
and show you. How does that sound?
一起穿给你看行不行
Don't be upset anymore.
别生气了
You've got dark circles under your eyes.
黑眼圈怎么那么大呀
Have you been staying up late again?
最近又熬夜了
It's OK.
没事
I just joined the force recently.
最近不是刚入职吗
There's a lot to learn.
很多东西需要学
It's fine.
没事
So it's deal.
那就这么说定了
You'll soon
你很快就会
buy those shoes back.
把那双鞋买回来
It's a promise.
说好了
Don't be upset.
别生气了
Let's go.
走吧
That's more like it.
这还差不多
Buy them back ASAP.
赶紧给我买回来啊
It's finally done.
终于弄完了
The working spirit of a laborer...
这打工人打工魂
No one knows when
也不知道什么时候
I'll be able to make a fortune.
才能挣到家财万贯哪
One, two...
一 二
One more time.
我再看一看
Think.
想一下
Who is it?
谁呀
Hello?
喂
It takes you forever to answer a call.
接个电话费你半天劲
Are you afraid I'll hound you
是怕我缠着你
or something?
还是怎么着啊
Who is this?
谁呀
It's stingy dude!
铁公鸡
Have you been drinking?
你这是喝了
Yeah...
喝了
I found your name tag.
我捡着你工牌了
Nothing else,
没别的事
just wanted to let you know.
就是告诉你一声
I was worried you might panic.
怕你找不到着急
I'm hanging up now.
挂了啊
No rush.
不着急
You can keep it for yourself.
你自己留着吧
Just let it stay there and have babies.
放你那儿生崽吧
I'm home now.
我到家了
Are you OK?
你没事吧
Have you made it home?
你到家了吗
Where are you?
你在哪儿呢
Hello?
喂
At the door,
门口
there's a pair
有一双
of size 42 men's shoes.
四十二码的男鞋
Don't forget to
你别给我
put them there.
忘了放那儿啊
Then tomorrow morning,
然后明天早上
after you get up,
睡醒以后呢
change the password
把我家那个
for my lock of
密码锁的密码
the door.
你给我改一下
Got it.
好嘞
Change the password.
换密码
Your security awareness
你这安全意识
is quite impressive.
倒是挺强的
Isn't it necessary to be cautious?
那不强能行吗
A beautiful woman living alone.
一个美女独居
You know what,
你知道吗
one time at my apartment,
有一次我家里
the elevator broke down.
电梯坏了
I had to take the stairs to get up.
我就爬楼梯上来
You know what I saw
你知道我在楼梯间
in the stairwell?
看见什么了
What?
什么
A huge graffiti of
这么大的一个
a naked woman.
裸胸女的标志
How frightening and provocative!
多吓人多色情啊
Then what happened?
然后呢
Then,
然后
the next day, I wiped it off.
第二天姐把它给擦了
But my house
但是我家
still got robbed.
怎么还是被偷了呀
Fortunately, I was at the office that day,
还好那天我在公司
working late.
熬夜加班
Otherwise,
要不你说
what if that thief
那小偷
was tempted
要是贪图姐的美色
by my beauty?
怎么办
At least you were safe.
好歹人没事
You were lucky.
万幸
Lucky?
万幸个屁
What's so lucky about it?
还万幸
Stingy dude.
铁公鸡
Why am I sharing all this
你说我跟你说这些
with you?
干吗呀
[That wasn't fun at all.]
这些有什么好说的
You're a fun dude.
因为你有意思
That's why I'm telling you all this.
姐才跟你说的
Don't laugh.
你别笑
Actually, you're not that fun.
不对你没意思
You need to be
你得跟
with me
姐在一起
to be fun.
才有意思
Hey,
干吗呀
knock it off.
你别跟我来这套啊
I'm not falling for that.
我最不吃这套了
Do two people really
你说两个人
have to be together?
非得在一起吗
Once you're together,
在一起以后
a lot more problems arise.
就增加了好多问题
More responsibilities,
责任变多
burdens multiply,
负担变多
it all becomes a hassle.
全是累赘
You might even end up breaking up.
你搞不好还要分手
And after a breakup,
分手以后
you won't even be friends.
连朋友都没得做了
Not even someone to banter with.
连个斗嘴的人都没有
How dull is that?
多无趣啊
If you haven't thought it through, fine.
没想清楚就算了吧
I'm heading home.
我回家了
You should get some rest.
你赶紧睡觉
Once my stepping out,
一会我到门口
you lock the door
你把门
from the inside.
在里边反锁了
I'll be off after hearing you tap it.
敲敲门我再走
You care about me so much,
你都这么关心我了
why do you still want to leave?
干吗还要走
Have you thought it through?
你想好了
Forget about thinking!
想什么想
Why is this so hard to take off.
这怎么这么难解呀
Next time,
下次能不能
can you wear something with
你穿个带
a zipper?
拉 拉链
Rao Jing.
饶静
Is that it?
这就完了
Qi Yu posted
齐郁发了
the photo of the two of them.
他们两个的合影
Looks like they're good now.
看来是和好了
Qi Yu returned
齐郁把凌惟依的鞋
the shoes Ling Weiyi bought.
给退回去了
Actually, I think
其实我倒觉得
it's a good thing.
是个好事儿
Think about it.
你想呀
When two people are dating,
两个人在一起
they should make progress, right?
总要一起进步吧
You can't always live your life
不能 永远把日子
like it's just a game.
过得像过家家一样
Right?
是吧
Is it
是不是
not going well
惟纪的事情
with Weiji's case?
谈得不太顺利呀
You got me on that.
被你看出来了
It's a bit tough.
确实是有一点
If no one can make a breakthrough
没人能够在方案上
in the proposal,
有所突破的话
no one could
就没人能够
really impress Mr. Xia.
真正打动夏总
But you know,
但是你也知道
the offers from
其实各家银行给出的
various banks are pretty much the same.
营销方案都差不多
We've already hit a wall.
已经拉扯到了极限
This is a deadlock.
这就是个死局
Someone needs to break it.
得有人破局才行
I spent
我今天下午
the entire afternoon
用了一下午的时间
thinking about it.
想了很多
But I still can't find a
但始终都找不到一个
better way out of this.
更好的办法能够破局
If
如果说
I can't secure the deal with Weiji,
真的拿不下惟纪的话
I could just kiss the position of
集安分行行长的竞选
the president of Jian Branch goodbye.
也就悬了
In the coming years,
未来的几年
I could only hold on to
我只能守着
the position of department manager,
部门经理的位置
with no prospects ahead.
一眼都能望到头
And one more thing,
还有一点
I actually don't want Xing Zhen
其实我也不想邢振
to take the position of president.
坐上行长的位置
Don't worry.
不着急
Take your time.
慢慢想
I have confidence in you anyway.
反正我对你有信心
You are Ji Yuheng, after all.
你可是纪昱恒啊
To be honest,
说真的
the pressure is really intense.
压力真的很大
Give me a hug.
抱一下
Let's go.
走吧
Go.
走
[You're so young and already managers.]
这么年轻都是经理
[Please take good care]
那就请你们在单位
[of her at work.]
多照顾照顾她
[This kid]
我们家这孩子呀
[is really]
人呢
[kind-hearted.]
又善良
[Sorry, Mr. Ji, there's ]
不好意思啊纪总
[only one cup of Aurelio White left.]
就剩一杯澳瑞白了
[Fine, I'll take it.]
给我吧没关系
[Yuheng, that's Aurelio White.]
师哥那杯是澳瑞白
[It's actually quite good.]
还挺好喝
While Yuheng's mom
趁着师哥妈妈
was sick,
生病这段时间
you really put in a lot of effort.
你没少下功夫啊
Tu Xiaoning,
涂筱柠
I underestimated you.
我小看你了
This is good enough.
力道刚刚好
Don't need to go harder.
不能再重了
By the way,
对了
Zhao Fang just texted me.
刚才赵方刚跟我发消息
He said the proposals from
他说申同跟光明
Shentong and Guangming
两家银行的方案
have been rejected already.
已经被明确拒绝了
Mr. Xia didn't show up,
夏总人是没出面
but had the accounting department
直接让财务
send a
发了一个
confirmation message.
确认信息
With two rivals out,
少了两家竞争银行
that's a good thing.
好事呀
Mr. Ji,
纪总
you're one step closer to success.
你离成功又近了一步
Based on this theory of yours,
那要按照你这理论
I don't need to prepare at all.
我都不需要做准备了
I can just rely on luck.
就靠运气
If luck is on my side,
运气要是好的话
I might just make it
说不定能苟活到
to the final round.
最后一轮呢
Some things are just like that.
有些事情那就是这样的
This is known as the law of attraction.
这叫吸引力法则
As long as you keep
只要你每天调整好心情
a positive attitude every day
保持一个好的状态
good things
好事情
will come your way.
就会主动找上门的
Like what?
那比如说呢
For instance,
比如说
Miss Tu saw that you
涂小姐看你现在
need to lift your spirits,
需要调整心情
and she wants to cheer you up,
想让你开心
so she comes over to comfort you.
就过来安慰你
Does that count?
算不算
Absolutely.
当然算
Come on,
来
it's my turn to give you a massage.
我给你按一按吧
Just relax.
放松 放松
Actually,
其实呢
when it comes to adjusting your mindset
在调整心态
and encouraging yourself,
鼓励自己这方面吧
I could be your mentor.
我可以算是你的导师了
You could be my what?
你刚刚说可以是我什么
A mentor.
导师
I actually thought of
我还真想到了
a good angle.
一个切入点
Yes, Miss Fang.
是的方小姐
Come on, I'm in a good mood today.
来吧姐今儿心情好
Who hasn't had breakfast?
谁没吃早餐
Go ahead, have some.
分一下
Good morning, Jing.
早啊静姐
Thank you, Jing.
谢谢静姐
Morning.
早
You recovered from the hangover fast!
酒醒得挺快的啊
I'm not like the others, can't even
那咱不像别人喝个酒
walk a straight line when drunk.
连个直线都走不了
Looks like you don't remember
看来昨天晚上的事
anything from last night.
你什么都不记得了
Last night?
昨天晚上
What happened last night?
昨天晚上什么事
What should I remember?
我应该记得什么
Let me think.
我想想啊
Oh yeah,
对
did I tell you to
我是不是说让你
remind me to change the password?
提醒我改密码
I changed it when I went out this morning.
我早上出门改过了
Miss!
饶
Rao,
经理
here is the information on the client,
这是那个客户资料
take a look.
你看一看
You scared me.
吓我一大跳
You really should go check out
真该去医院查一查
this problem of
你这喝了酒
blacking out after drinking.
就断片的臭毛病
Why else would you drink?
不断片谁喝酒啊
Yes,
对
you can come directly to the
方小姐您直接到分行
sub-branch to find me, Miss Fang.
来找我就行
Do you have my electronic business card?
您有我的电子名片吧
Okay.
好
Then I'll see you here.
那我等您
Yes, okay.
好的 好的
Goodbye.
拜拜
Jing,
静姐
I've been working
我营销了一个叫
with a client named Fang Xiaoyun.
方小云的客户
[But this Miss Fang]
但是这个方小姐
[is already in the system.]
系统里是有的
She has been under Yao Jia's name
挂在了二部姚佳名下
in Section Two for two years.
两年了
But the account is not even activated,
连准入都没有做
nor there is any company information.
企业信息也没有
What should I do?
那我应该怎么办呀
Normally, you need to fill out
按照惯例你要填写
an account transfer request.
一个调户申请
And then just transfer Yao Jia's
然后把那个姚佳的
personal data
个人资料
over to you.
调过来就可以了
Hello, Yao Jia.
喂 姚佳姐
I'm Tu Xiaoning, from Section One.
我是一部的涂筱柠
Today I was talking with a client
我今天营销了一个客户
named Fang Xiaoyun.
叫方小云
When I was registering her I saw that
录入的时候发现
you already opened an account for her
两年前你给她开的户
2 years ago, but it was never activated.
但是一直没有激活
Would it be
您看
convenient for you if we
今天方不方便
do the account transfer today?
做个调户啊
Transfer a client from my system?
调我系统里的客户
You're stealing in broad daylight.
你这明抢啊
[I don't get to make this decision.]
我做不了主啊
[Ask the boss.]
让领导定吧
It's been two years and it hasn't...
两年了没有
Poaching clients this blatantly.
这么明目张胆地抢人
[People would think]
不知道的以为
[that we are all robbers.]
我们一部全都是土匪呢
[Won't you be embarrassed if it gets out?]
传出去不嫌丢人
Why can't I
两年了
contact a client
都没有激活的客户
who hasn't been activated for two years?
我为什么不能联系
Didn't you hear what
你刚刚没有听
Jing just said?
饶静姐说吗
Tu Xiaoning,
涂筱柠
do you really not care at all
你真觉得你做的那些
[if those shameless things you did]
见不得人的事
[get out?]
传出去都无所谓吗
Do you think you'll still have a place
如果让行里知道
at this bank if everyone finds out?
你觉得容得下你吗
[What shameless things]
我做什么
[did I do?]
见不得人的事了
[I followed the regulations.]
我按规章办事
Why won't I have a place here?
行里为什么容不下我
You followed the regulations?
你按规章办事
Yuhui,
小唐
[you're being too harsh.]
言重了啊
It's not your client.
又不是你的客户
Even if you're in a bad mood,
心情不好
you shouldn't lash out at others.
也不能乱咬人啊
Did you all have a bad breakfast
不是我说这一大早上的
this morning or what!
你们一个个全吃炸药啦
[If the bank's president finds out,]
只要行长知道了
[he'll definitely let her go]
肯定会为了保全师哥
[to protect Yuheng.]
让她走人
[Who does she think she is,]
就这点本事
[seducing the department leader?]
也敢勾搭部门领导
[She really doesn't know her place!]
太不知道好歹了
[Yuheng,]
昱恒
[take a seat first.]
坐下说
[About the Weiji Group,]
惟纪公司的事情
I've thought about it more carefully.
我又好好想了想
Originally,
原本
Weiji Group's business
惟纪公司的事业版图
was centered in the U.S.
是在美国
[The domestic resort project]
国内的度假村项目
[started]
其实是三年前
[only three years ago.]
才刚刚开始做
But its development
但发展
lags far behind that of the U.S.
远远不及美国
So, I think for Mr. Xia,
所以我想对于夏总来说
having a financial expert
跟能融到多少钱比起来
who understands the domestic market
如果能有一个懂得
and can plan
国内市场环境的
how to use the funds well
财务专家
[for him]
替他
[is likely more important]
规划好
[than how much money]
如何用这笔钱
[can be raised.]
来得更为重要一些
Do we have any suitable candidates?
有合适的人选吗
My advisor from college,
我大学时期的导师
Jia Ziqing.
贾子庆
[Professor Jia is one]
贾老师是国内
[of the top economists in the country.]
首屈一指的经济学专家
[If we could get Professor Jia]
如果说能够请到贾老师
[to do the financial plan]
为惟纪公司度假村项目
for Weiji's resort project,
做一个财务规划的话
I think Mr. Xia might be interested.
我想夏总可能会感兴趣
[This is a good idea.]
这个主意很好
[But,]
但是
about your advisor.
你导师这边
I will go to Jinghai
周末的时候
this weekend
我会去趟京海
and invite him myself.
当面邀请他
Be quick.
下手要快
We can't let a big catch like Weiji
惟纪这条大鱼
slip away.
咱们可不能让它跑了
Understood.
明白
[I must have lost my mind from anger.]
我也真是被气糊涂了
[Why would I lower myself]
干什么要自降身价
[to Tu Xiaoning's level?]
跟涂筱柠啰嗦
[I should focus more on Yuheng]
该在师哥身上下功夫
[and let him see my value.]
让他看到我的价值才对
Hello,
喂
Mr. Jia?
贾老师吗
This is Yuhui.
我是羽卉
I'm doing well.
我挺好的
Just the usual banking stuff.
银行吗就是这些工作
I'm sure it's all nothing to you.
对您来说肯定都不是事
Yeah,
对
I want to ask you
我有些事情
for a favor.
想要拜托您一下
Do you have time on Saturday?
您周六有时间吗
I'll go visit you in Jinghai.
我去京海拜访您
Okay.
好
See you then.
那到时候见了
What happened?
什么事啊
Yao Jia came with Mr. Xing
邢总带着姚佳过来
to talk to you about
找你理论
the account transfer I did from Yao Jia.
我从姚佳那儿调户的事
Let's go see.
看看去
You do have the best tea here.
还是你这儿的茶好啊
I was wondering why all the bosses
我说领导怎么都喜欢
always come here for tea.
上你这儿来喝茶呢
Where did you get it?
在哪儿买的
Mr. Xing,
邢总
this is our company's tea.
这就是咱们公司的茶包
Mr. Ji,
纪总
I know that your department's
我知道现在你们部门
performance is great right now.
业绩做得很好
But isn't the Section One
可是你们拓展一部的手
overstepping a little?
会不会伸得有点太长了
[Xiaoning]
今天一早
[came to out department]
你们小涂
[early this morning,]
就到我们部门来
[demanding to transfer Yao Jia's client.]
调我们姚佳的客户
Isn't this
这是不是有点
a bit too much?
说不过去了
Really?
还有这种事啊
Xiaoning,
小涂
how did you get this client?
这客户是怎么拉到的
Mr. Liu from Longhu Glass,
我之前营销过的
with whom I've worked before,
龙虎玻璃的柳总
has also collaborated with Miss Fang.
和方小姐也有合作
[He's an upstream client of Miss fang.]
是方小姐的上游客户
[Miss fang thought]
后来方小姐发现
[the deposit plan]
我给柳总
[I did for Mr. Liu]
制定的存款方案
[was not bad.]
很不错
She was interested as well, so
也很感兴趣
she made an appointment to talk with me.
就约我聊了一下
And then
随后
she signed the cooperation agreement.
就签订了合作意向
Don't you have any shame at all?
你能不能要点脸啊
Sugarcoating client poaching
把撬客户
like that.
包装得那么好听
Here's the situation,
其实是这样
the thing is,
就是
this client
这个客户啊
was originally
原本就是
one of Yao Jia's clients.
在我们姚佳的手里的
[You transferred]
你在没有提前
[the client's information]
打招呼的情况下
without giving any prior notice,
调用客户信息
isn't this a bit
这是不是
against the rules?
不太符合规矩啊
Mr. Ji,
纪总
there's nothing wrong
你要搞业绩
with chasing better results,
没毛病
but anyway,
但不管怎么说
don't you think you should
是不是也得给我们这些
leave something for us
兄弟部门
in the other departments too?
留口饭吃
I don't really understand
邢总这话
what you're saying, Mr. Xing.
我就听不太懂了
According to the bank's regulations,
根据咱们行里的规定
if a client
这客户
is in a credit system
在一个信贷系统里面
[and isn't activated]
如果一年之内
[within a year,]
未被激活的话
[then they are considered a new client.]
是被称作新客户的
How can a client
我们小涂亲自
that Xiaoning found herself
拉到了业务
be considered poaching
怎么就成了
from you?
撬你们客户了
[And you even went to the trouble of]
还劳您兴师动众
[coming to Section One yourself?]
来到我们拓展一部
[Then you must have been]
你们这碗饭
struggling with this job.
也未免太不好吃了吧
How about this,
这样吧
we all work for
既然邢总也说了嘛
the same bank after all,
兄弟部门
let's not fight among ourselves.
我们就不搞内讧了
Xiaoning,
小涂
call that client.
给那个客户打个电话
Since we're all here,
趁着人都在
let the client choose herself.
让客户自己选
[If the client]
如果说客户
[prefers Section Two's]
希望是拓展二部的
[Miss Yao]
姚经理
[to take over,]
来接手的话
then we'll gladly
那咱们把这个客户
hand over this client.
双手奉上
Okay.
好
Fine, fine.
行 行
Do it, do it.
调 调 调
Do the transfer.
调啊
It's yours.
送你了
Section Two doesn't need
这种小户
such a minor client anyway.
我们二部不要也罢
Mr. Xing.
邢总
What are you still doing with
这种客户在自己手里面
such a client
两年一棍子
that hasn't brought in anything
都打不出来一个闷屁的
after two years?
你还留着她干什么呀
[If they want her,]
既然人家想要
[just hand it over]
你就大大方方地
[generously.]
送给人家嘛
Let's see if they can
看看这种客户
turn such clients into a gold mine
到了他们的手里
or what!
能折腾出什么金山银山
Go back now.
回去
Get back to work now.
先去忙吧
Okay.
好
Mr. Xing I'll get back to work then.
邢总我先去忙了
Mr. Xing, is there anything else?
邢总还有什么事啊
Mr. Ji,
纪总
let's not let the conflicts
这手底下的人闹矛盾哪
between our subordinates interfere with
可千万别来影响
the relationship between us brothers.
咱们兄弟之间的感情
[Brother,]
老弟
[look,]
你看啊
now I
哥哥呢
have given you the client,
现在是客户给你了
as well as
面子
the face.
我也给你了
Tell me the truth,
你给我交个实底
how did it go
惟纪公司那边
with Weiji Group?
你追得怎么样了
Weiji Group?
惟纪公司
To be honest,
真不瞒你说
I still haven't even been able to
我到现在为止
meet Mr. Xia in person yet.
都没见上这夏总的面呢
In the end,
其实啊
it's like you said,
就像你说的
[Weiji Group is nothing more than]
这惟纪公司无非就是个
[a client.]
客户而已
It's not like
这
if you don't sign this one,
又不是签不了这个单
you won't be able to
咱们这工作
keep this job anymore, right?
就没法干下去了对吧
[I think,]
要我说啊
[we should both]
咱哥俩
take it easy
都给自己解解锁
and not put
千万别给自己
too much pressure on ourselves,
那么大的压力
don't you think so?
你说是吧
So, Mr. Xing, you didn't really come over
原来邢总今天过来
for the transfer today, you came
调户的事是小
to convince me to give up on Weiji.
劝我放弃惟纪那是真啊
No.
没有
Sure,
行
I'll think about it.
我会好好考虑考虑
If Professor Jia agrees
如果贾老师能同意
to be Weiji Group's
做惟纪公司的
financial advisor,
财务顾问的话
then Weiji will surely
那惟纪肯定会
collaborate with us.
跟我们合作的
I agree with
你说的这点
what you said as well.
我跟你想法一样
Looks like students of the same teacher
看来同门的师兄妹
do share
还是有
a sense of mutual understanding.
心灵相通的地方的
Anything else?
还有别的事吗
I'm going to visit Professor Jia
我这周六约了贾老师
at university this Saturday.
去学校看他
If you're going
你要是也是
this weekend as well,
这周末去的话
let's go together.
咱俩一起
We're from the same company
咱俩一个单位的
and the same department,
又是一个部门
it would be very strange
同一天去
if we go separately
还要分开的话
on the same day.
也太奇怪了
Sure.
行
I'll take care of the plane tickets.
那我来安排订票
I'll send you
订票信息
the booking information later.
稍后发给你
Yuheng,
师哥
do you think
你有没有觉得
there are too many different
咱们部门的人
people in our department?
有点太杂了
It's about quality
一个部门的人
not quantity.
在精不在多
I know you.
我了解你
You like challenges,
你喜欢挑战
but you always handle things
但是做事情
with integrity.
一定是光明磊落
Yuhui, if you do know me,
小唐你如果了解我
then you should know that
就应该知道
the thing I dislike the most
我最不喜欢的
is the people who
就是自己部门的人
make mischief in their own department.
搬弄是非
The bank has clear regulations,
行里有明确的规定
we should handle clients
对于客户
according to the rules.
我们就照章办事
No,
不是
that's not what I meant.
我不是这个意思
I mean,
我是说
some people,
像有些人
like Tu Xiaoning,
比如说涂筱柠那种
would poach someone else's client
为了区区一百万的存款
[for a mere million, they]
就去别人家挖客户
[even came to our department for this.]
都让人家怼到脸上来了
[It's really quite disgraceful.]
实在是很不体面
Mr. Ji.
纪总好
Yuhui,
小唐啊
there are always ways to vent
人心情不好呢
when you're in a bad mood.
十有八九是可以发泄的
But you already picked on Xiaoning
但是早上你在办公室
this morning at the office.
就已经找了小涂的茬了
[And now after work,]
现在已经下班了
[you're still stabbing her in the back]
你还在纪总面前
[in front of Mr. Ji.]
背后捅了小涂一刀
[I really do think]
我确实觉得
this is a bit inappropriate.
这么做有点不太合适了
Jing,
静姐
I didn't stab
我没有背后
anyone in the back.
捅任何人刀子
I'm just stating the facts.
我只是实事求是说实话
And speaking of facts,
说实话
there was no such thing as
抢客户这种事情呢
poaching clients,
根本就不存在
so you don't need to
所以这个事儿
bring this up anymore.
可以不用提了
A mere million?
区区一百万
[One of the most important aspects]
尽心尽力为银行拉存款
about our job is to bring in
是我们最重要的
more deposits for the bank diligently.
工作之一
Over the years,
而且这么多年了
Xu Li, Mr. Zhao, and I
我许力还有赵经理
have all been focused on bringing in
都是给银行
deposits, issuing loans, and accumulating
拉存款放贷款
clients and resources for the bank.
积累客户做资源
Right, Mr. Zhao?
是吧赵经理
Here's the thing,
是这样的
if Xiaoning
这个客户
didn't contact this client,
小涂要是不联系
whom Yao Jia hasn't activated for years,
姚佳放着几年不激活
then we would lose
那这个客户
this client, right?
不就流失了吗
Okay then.
行
If there's nothing else,
没什么事的话
let's all leave.
先散了吧
Working overtime in the underground
在地下车库里加班
parking garage doesn't get you extra pay.
可没加班费
I'll leave too.
那我也走了
Can you fix an electricity meter?
会修电表吗
I said, can you fix an electricity meter?
我问你会修电表吗
Your electricity meter is broken?
电表坏了
Yes.
坏了
The circuit breaker keeps tripping lately.
这几天总跳闸
I tried to fix it for a few days.
然后我自己修了几天
But I couldn't.
没有修好
If you have some time
你这个周末
this weekend,
要是有时间的话
will you come fix it for me?
过来帮我修一下呗
Why are you asking me instead of
电表坏了不找电表师傅
looking for an electrician?
找我干吗呀
You don't want to?
不愿意呀
Fine.
行
I'm mainly concerned about your money.
主要是我心疼你的钱
[See you on the weekend.]
周末见
Mr. Xing hasn't made things difficult
邢总没有再为调户的事
to you about the client transfer,
为难你吧
and bothered you anymore, right?
让你心烦
No.
没有
Good then.
那就好
Actually he knew very well
其实是非论断
what's right and what's wrong.
他心里都很清楚的
In the future, when it comes to work,
以后工作上呀
you should fight when needed.
该争还是得争一下
Or all your hard work
要不然你所有的努力
would become a stepping stone for others.
都是给别人做嫁衣
Yao Jia was not cooperative at first
姚佳她起初不配合
was also because
也是因为
she saw the potential.
她看到了业绩
If we let something like this slide
如果这种事情让一次
this time, then
以后他们
they'll just keep pushing their luck
都会蹬鼻子上脸
and it will never end.
没完没了地
Oh right,
对了
I booked a ticket
我订了周五下班以后
for a business trip
要出差一趟的票
after work this Friday to Jinghai
去京海
with
跟
Tang Yuhui.
唐羽卉一起
Professor Jia was her advisor as well.
贾老师也是她的导师
She contacted him first.
她先联系了
It's more appropriate if we go together.
一起去会比较合适一点
I didn't say anything.
我没说什么呀
Mr. Ji,
纪先生
you're very cautious now.
你现在很谨慎吗
But don't worry.
不过放心吧
I booked a ticket for you as well.
我也给你订了一张票
What do you mean?
什么意思
I'm going too?
我也要去啊
Wouldn't it be strange
三个人一起去
if the three of us go together?
不会很奇怪吗
Plus Tang Yuhui is pretty smart.
而且唐羽卉她挺聪明的
What if she finds out?
万一发现了怎么办啊
It's the weekend anyway.
反正是周末
I'll take you out and show you around
等我忙完了
Jinghai when I'm done working.
带你从京海到处逛逛
Actually it's fine.
其实没事的
I won't overthink.
我不会多想的
Okay.
好了
Don't worry.
放心吧
I already planned everything.
我都已经安排好了
Consider it
就当作是
a short trip
短途旅行
to relax yourself,
放松 放松
okay?
好不好
Okay.
好
Let's go.
走
Can you still run?
还能跑吗
This way, please.
这边请
Welcome abroad.
欢迎登机
Hello, ma'am,
你好女士
do you need help with your bag?
包需要放一下吗
Yes.
可以
Okay.
好
[Mr. Ji,]
纪先生
[you're way too bold now,]
你现在也太大胆了
[you bought the same flight?]
竟敢买同架航班
[It's not okay?]
不好吗
[Aren't you afraid]
你就不怕
[Tang Yuhui will find out?]
被唐羽卉发现
[It's okay.]
没事
[I just wanted to take you]
主要想带你一起
[to see my old university.]
回我的大学看看
Yuheng,
师哥
when you went to talk about
你上次
the Zhouyang contract last time,
去聊洲洋合同的时候
did you have a reunion
跟京海的老同学
with our old classmates at Jinghai?
有没有聚一聚
I didn't.
还真没有
Last time I was in a hurry.
上次的时间比较仓促
Well then,
那
perfect.
刚好
I want to organize a reunion with
这两天空的时候
our classmates when we're free these days,
我想叫上同学们
just to talk and catch up.
一块聚一聚聊一聊
Tomorrow is the weekend, you're
明天是周末
free to do anything with your own time.
你的时间可以自行安排
If they want,
如果他们愿意的话
I can be the financial advisor
我可以做这个
for this financing project.
融资项目的财务顾问
That would be great!
那可真是太好了
Thank you, Professor Jia.
谢谢您了贾老师
[You've really helped us a lot.]
帮了我们一个大忙
Professor,
老师
when you come to Xing City,
等您去星城的时候
Yuheng and I
我跟师哥
will definitely show you around.
一定好好带您逛逛
Okay.
好
I might just take you up on it.
到时候我可赖上你们
Are you two
你们俩
close to sealing the deal?
是不是好事近了
Professor, don't make jokes.
老师您别开玩笑了
[You're still this gossipy.]
怎么还是这么八卦呀
Back in school,
之前在学校系里的时候
there were already some students
就有同学
spreading rumors about me and Yuheng.
传我跟师哥的绯闻
It must've been you who started it, right?
当时就是您说出去的吧
[Professor Jia,]
贾老师
Yuhui and I
我跟小唐
are just colleagues.
只是普通的同事关系
Yeah.
对
Yuheng's right.
师哥说得对
[We are indeed]
我们现在呀
just colleagues now.
就是普通同事关系
He's a bit thin-skinned, Professor.
他脸皮薄教授
[Stop joking around.]
您别开玩笑
[I got it.]
我明白了
[Yuheng,]
小纪啊
in relationships,
感情这种事啊
it's better for men
还是男人主动一些
to take the initiative.
比较好
Be steady, decisive, and precise.
下手要稳 狠 准
Otherwise,
不然
a great girl can be easily
好姑娘很容易
taken away by someone else.
就被别人抢走了
No...
不是
It's already late.
都这个点了
As your professor,
本来你们过来
I should
我当老师的
take you out to dinner
怎么也应该
when you come here.
带你们吃个饭
But today is Saturday.
但今天周六
My grandson's in an early education class.
我孙子上早教班
[I need to go pick him up.]
嘱咐了我去接
[We'll]
咱们
just have to wait until I go to Xing city.
只能等我到星城再聚了
Sure.
行
Professor Jia, you go ahead.
那贾老师您先忙
We'll wait for you in Xing city.
我们在星城等着您
Okay.
好
Okay, goodbye.
好 再见
Goodbye.
再见
Today is not the right time anyway.
今天的时机也不太合适
Next time,
等下次
when Professor Jia goes to Xing city,
贾老师去了星城
I'll explain our relationship
我会跟他解释清楚
to him clearly.
我们之间的关系
Actually I think some of the things
其实我觉得贾老师
Professor Jia said make sense.
说得有些话还是挺对的
You should indeed know someone inside and
找对象吗
out when it comes to finding a partner.
就得知根知底
This is where we
这儿就是我们
met for the first time.
第一次见面的地方
A big package
当时有一个大型的快递
fell down from up there.
从上面掉下来
Do you still remember?
你还记得吗
C'mon!
你快点
Xiaoning,
筱柠
I think he's in charge of discipline.
他好像是校干部的
I saw.
我看见了呀
Looks like you need to hurry.
看来得稍微快点了
[Being 10 minutes late]
迟到十分钟
would be considered an absence.
就算旷课了
Thank you.
谢谢你啊
This is my favorite, egg yolk pastry.
我最喜欢的蛋黄酥
As a thank you gift.
当谢礼了
Thank you.
谢谢